Murtaza Jabalpurwala

Business Development Analyst and Sales

Digital Entrepreneurial business professional with over 8 years of experience with success in a business start-up, optimizing with digitalization and maximizing revenues with strategic leadership. Expertise in B2B Sales, purchasing retail and negotiations, logistics industries, account management, retail marketing, merchandising, store management, sales, client-vendor relations, and ability to implement strategies to maximize growth. I am interested in advancing my career in Business development and upgrade my technical skill-set.



murtazajits@gmail.com 🗍 +49-1773420450



Berlin, Germany

in linkedin.com/in/murtaza-jabalpurwala-

WORK EXPERIENCE

Business Development and Sales

Expatrio

09/2020 - Present

Berlin, Germany

Regional Manager for Asian market

- Constant acquisition of new customers and maintenance of relationships.
- Performing cold calling and B2B webinars from bringing more partners.
- Defined and implemented an operational strategy for commercial development as a regional manager.
- Search for potential customers and approach them by running email campaigns. Manage your activities using the CRM.
- Synthesize market data with collected observations to bring insights on how partner offerings and account management can be improved.

Contact: Mr. Dominic (MD & Cofounder)

Entrepreneur/Business Owner

Noble Shoe Co.

04/2012 - 10/2019

Gandhinagar, India

- Analyzed processed and found creative solutions to overcame challenges with old School legacy-based business being run for 30 years (retail) and converted it into a Digital business which can be controlled remotely only through the use of an android smartphone.
- gathered defined and requirements specifications. Designed this application with creativity, starting with acquisition and along the whole software development process – from design through development and to test and implementing it in the running system.
- Worked closely with management team to create end-to-end CRM marketing campaigns.
- Business Optimization projects. Scaling Business model. Measurable outcomes (KPIs).

20% revenue growth	70% decrease in working
	hours of owner
Up to 60% in efficiency gains	80% paperless business

Junior Business Analyst

Serpent Consulting Services

05/2010-03/2012

Gandhinagar, India

Led the effort of analyzing and defining system requirements, business rules, creating analyses, pitch decks and business plan requirements for several key components.

TECHNICAL SKILLS



PROJECTS

Designed an entire application to automate a retail store and operate the business only through an android application. This visionary move made the owner work from home and increased sales dramatically, reducing monthly work hours from 260 to 50.

Organizational / Managerial Skills

- Leadership Skills (Managed a team of 14 people in Noble Shoe Co.)
- Sponsored speaker at 2 public conferences for an audience of all vertical levels Veer Electronics Expo & CEI Expo.

LANGUAGES

MOTHER TONGUE(S):

Hindi C2 Gujarati C2

OTHER LANGUAGE:

English C2 German A2 **Fluent** Good knowledge

EDUCATION

Global MBA

Berlin School of Business & Innovation (BSBI)

10/2019 - 04/2021 Berlin, Germany

Specialization in Project Management

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics & Communication Geetanjali Institute of Technical Studies (GITS)

05/2016 - 04/2010 Udaipur, India

INTERESTS

Traveling Yoga

Reading